<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guild Mortgage with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 13:40:17 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 13:40:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Freeze Your Own Credit</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bKB5EQWW-YU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever had your credit pulled without your permission or you’re worried about identity theft happening to you, a new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit if you want to.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part? You can do it for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit if you want to.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-you-can-freeze-your-own-credit.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A new federal law was recently passed that allows you to freeze your credit if you want to.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All you have to do is contact all three major credit bureaus—Transunion, Equifax, and Experian—by phone, written mail, or online, and ask them to lock down your credit.&lt;/strong&gt; If you make this request online or by phone, your credit will be frozen within one day. If you do it through written mail, your credit will be frozen within three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, if you want to unfreeze your credit at anytime, all you have to do it contact them again and ask.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this topic or there’s anything else I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk, and I’d be happy to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:42:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-you-can-freeze-your-own-credit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-you-can-freeze-your-own-credit.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Exciting New Loan From Guild Mortgage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3ezuEb5nIAc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to talk about Guild Mortgage’s new “3, 2, 1” mortgage program. This exciting new loan program could be just what you’re looking for as a homebuyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the basics: It’s a 30-year fixed conventional loan that requires a 3% down payment and a credit score of at least 620.&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond that, the loan may also only be used to purchase a pre-owned property.  But wait, there’s more. In addition to a lower down payment, Guild Mortgage will also give the buyer an additional $1,500 to use towards their down payment, closing costs, or whatever else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In addition to a lower down payment, Guild Mortgage will also provide an additional $1,500 to be used toward the down payment or closing costs.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/an-exciting-new-loan-from-guild-mortgage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In addition to a lower down payment, Guild Mortgage will also provide an additional $1,500 to be used toward the down payment or closing costs.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, when the loan closes, &lt;strong&gt;this program also gives you a $2,000 Home Depot gift&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;card&lt;/strong&gt; that you can use to buy appliances, furniture, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted everyone to know about this fantastic program that might be the perfect fit for you, a friend, a family member, or someone else you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me, feel free to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. Remember, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 13:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/an-exciting-new-loan-from-guild-mortgage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/an-exciting-new-loan-from-guild-mortgage.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zero-Down Home Financing for the Rural Homebuyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yyhUq-X7a9k?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to take a closer look at USDA home loans and the benefits they bring to homebuyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A USDA home loan is a loan guaranteed by the U.S. Department of Agriculture.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn’t work everywhere, however—the purpose the of the program is to help with financing homes in rural areas. You will not get approved for this loan inside a city with a population of more than 25,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a type of conventional loan, the USDA loan uses a conventional appraisal. Similar to the VA loan, &lt;strong&gt;it doesn’t require a down payment at all.&lt;/strong&gt; The borrower must have a 620 credit score (at least with my company), and there will be a small private mortgage insurance amount that you will be expected to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The USDA home loan program is a great product if used properly.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/zero-down-home-financing-for-the-rural-homebuyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The USDA home loan program is a great product if used properly.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all USDA home loans, there is a maximum family income. This varies based on the location of the home, which is why you need to make sure to check with your loan officer. For example, &lt;strong&gt;in the San Antonio area, the maximum income for a family of four cannot exceed $82,700 in order to be eligible for the USDA loan.&lt;/strong&gt; Of course, larger families have higher maximum incomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The USDA home loan program is a great product if used properly, and it has helped many families in less populous areas in the nation. To find out if a home you are looking at qualifies for a USDA loan, you can go &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://eligibility.sc.egov.usda.gov/eligibility/welcomeAction.do#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about it, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 10:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/zero-down-home-financing-for-the-rural-homebuyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/zero-down-home-financing-for-the-rural-homebuyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Credit Repair Companies Do to Fix Your Score</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BfZxYEYaPJQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to talk about credit repair. What is it? And how can it help fix your credit score?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I get to that, however, I want to talk about the things that cause credit problems. Obviously, late payments and collections both contribute to a negative credit score. More recently, I have also seen broken apartment leases negatively impacting people’s credit scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is the common misconception that when you pay off a past-due bill,  it is no longer on your credit report. This is wrong because &lt;strong&gt;even if you have a $0 balance, the damage is done&lt;/strong&gt; and it is still reporting as either a derogatory or late payment on your credit report. In fact, it will remain on your report for seven years unless you or a credit repair company works on removing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else that you need to know is that 83% of all credit reports today have errors of some kind on them. These can be anything from the wrong dates being reported, the months that you have paid off not being present, or items that aren’t even yours appearing on your report. It’s important to be aware of these errors because your score can make or break your ability to obtain a mortgage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Credit repair companies basically bombard the credit bureaus with letters questioning every negative thing on your credit report.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-credit-repair-companies-do-to-fix-your-score.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Credit repair companies basically bombard the credit bureaus with letters questioning every negative thing on your credit report.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what actually does credit repair do to help you? Credit repair companies basically bombard credit bureaus with letters questioning every negative thing on your credit report. Is it effective? Absolutely, because, under federal law, the credit bureaus have just 30 days to respond back and clarify whether that item is really true or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the creditors do not respond within 30 days, federal law requires that the negative item come off your credit score permanently.&lt;/strong&gt; Since the credit repair companies question these things, the bureaus have no choice but to remove it from your report if they do not get a response in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should know that there are lots of people in the credit repair business that take your money and then not do anything. &lt;strong&gt;You need to be very careful with who you hire to do this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can always refer you to several credit repair specialists I’ve worked with successfully who do a wonderful job. Or, you can ask around and get some references from people that have used them personally. You want to be sure that they are people who know what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 13:12:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-credit-repair-companies-do-to-fix-your-score.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-credit-repair-companies-do-to-fix-your-score.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Knowing Your Deductible</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WSaGXnZchZg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know what your insurance deductible is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, people tend to select a 1% rate in case of things like hail or fire damage. This means that if someone with a 1% annual rate has a $250,000 home, then their deductible would amount to $2,500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in some cases, &lt;strong&gt;people may take shortcuts and attempt to get a lower annual rate on their insurance premium by selecting a rate of 2% or 3%.&lt;/strong&gt; This can land you in hot water, though. To explain why, I’d like to recount a scenario I encountered recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The last thing you want to do is cut corners to save a few pennies up front, only to wind up paying for a major expense later on as a result.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/the-importance-of-knowing-your-deductible.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The last thing you want to do is cut corners to save a few pennies up front, only to wind up paying for a major expense later on as a result.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just last week I had a client who was selling his $250,000 home. When the inspector came out to examine the home, he declared the roof to be a total loss as the result of hail damage. My client picked up the phone and called their insurance company, who sent out an adjuster that agreed with the inspector’s claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the client had selected a 2% rate rather than a 1% rate, &lt;strong&gt;he will be forced to pay $5,000 of the total $10,000 that’s needed to repair the roof.&lt;/strong&gt; It just goes to show how quickly things can creep up on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that you’ve got to make sure you know what your insurance policy and exposure actually is. The last thing you want to do is cut corners to save a few pennies up front, only to wind up paying for a major expense later on as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 10:28:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/the-importance-of-knowing-your-deductible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/the-importance-of-knowing-your-deductible.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Home Warranties Are so Important</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QKJ6tuUkhs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a home today, receiving a clean report from the home inspector does not mean you are out of the woods. &lt;strong&gt;Systems or appliances in your home could fail a week, a month, or even years down the line.&lt;/strong&gt; And they may no longer be under warranty, meaning that you will be the one to pay if something goes wrong. That is, if you do not have a home warranty policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a home warranty policy can protect you from such expenses. &lt;strong&gt;You will be offered such a policy at closing, but it is still possible to obtain a home warranty even after this point.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense. Systems and appliances like stoves, dishwashers, garage door openers, air conditioning units, water heaters, and more are among the items these policies cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, given how catastrophic a cost replacing or repairing these items could be, it is clear why a home warranty is so critical. Think of it this way: Wouldn’t you rather pay a fixed cost for a home warranty policy each year rather than shelling out who knows how much for an unexpected disaster? There are some exceptions, but &lt;strong&gt;for the most part, the only cost you pay when ordering a repair through your home warranty policy is the charge for the service call.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last decade as a homeowner, I have had two air conditioning units, my dishwasher, my garbage disposal, and my garage door spring all fail. You never know when a system or appliance in your home may fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if a standard policy isn’t sufficient for your needs, you may consider signing up for a premium or enhanced policy. These offer even more protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between your real estate agent and title company, you will have access to a wealth of knowledge and resources in the process of selecting which home warranty policy is right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 14:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Homeowner’s Insurance Policy Should You Choose?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFzjL8xCMoE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of questions about homeowners insurance from clients as well as Realtors. So, today I’d like to discuss a few important points about this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates are going up sharply due to some pretty massive national losses from a lot of the insurance companies. Hurricane flooding in Houston and other natural disasters in California are creating massive claims for insurance companies, driving up the costs. But, you should know that &lt;strong&gt;if you are going to finance the home, homeowner’s insurance is mandatory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, insurance companies try to get your business by offering you a low rate. However, they increase the deductible over the usual 1% deductible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you have a $250,000 house with a total roof loss due to hail and a new roof costs $10,000. To reach your deductible you will have to pay $2,500, which means you will get a check for $7,500 to pay for your roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you elected to take a 2% or even a 3% deductible, you are going to get next to nothing for that roof. Since the roof still needs to be repaired, this can take a major toll on your checkbook. For this reason, you should &lt;strong&gt;be careful what deductible you select&lt;/strong&gt; when you choose coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should select a policy with a 1% deductible even if it has a higher rate because if something does happen a higher deductible could mean you spend more.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should select a policy with a 1% deductible even if it has a higher rate because if something does happen a higher deductible could mean you spend more.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many coverage options available today. &lt;strong&gt;You should select replacement coverage.&lt;/strong&gt; This type of coverage means that if you have a fire and all of your furniture is destroyed, you will get brand-new furniture even though it may be old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation, sometimes called slab, coverage will protect you from cracking due to covered events.&lt;/strong&gt; You also want water coverage for any seepage of water or broken pipes in the slab. Water can cause a tremendous amount of damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What controls the rates you get, though? &lt;strong&gt;Credit scores, the age of the home, the age of the roof, and location all influence your rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people also wonder about bundling their insurance and if they will get a deal. When you combine your auto insurance and homeowners insurance with the same company, you can get discounts on both. Always ask for the bundle deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about insurance, you can go to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opic.texas.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Office of Public Insurance Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;’s website. Here, they have information about homeowners insurance broken down into coverage, what it means, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions for me, please feel free to contact me by phone or email. I would be happy to assist in any way that I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Things to Avoid Doing During the Loan Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HlHj2u-q6nk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick rundown of the top 12 things you should not do during the loan process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Quit your job (or change jobs).&lt;/strong&gt; Why is this important? The day before closing, we have to call your employer to make sure you’re still there. If you quit, retire, or change jobs, that will be known the day before closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Buy a new car.&lt;/strong&gt; All mortgage companies have to do a soft credit pull the day of or the day before closing to make sure you haven’t taken on any new debt. If you purchase a new car, that will be revealed during a soft credit pull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Max out your credit card(s).&lt;/strong&gt; If you max out any credit cards, the minimum payment on your credit report goes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Let any collections show up on your credit report.&lt;/strong&gt; Even something as small as a co-pay at the doctor’s office can upset your approval because that collection can cost you 30 to 40 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Spend the money you set aside for your closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; Believe it or not, this does happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you avoid doing any of these things during the loan process.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/12-things-to-avoid-doing-during-the-loan-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you avoid doing any of these things during the loan process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Omit any liabilities (childcare costs, private land payments, etc.).&lt;/strong&gt; Eventually, these will come out, and it’s much better if we know about them up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Buy any major appliances or furniture a day or two before closing.&lt;/strong&gt; I know it’s tempting to do so, but if you take on any debt during the loan process, we’ll have to count that payment. Even if the payment is interest-only, we still have to count it on the credit report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Apply for more credit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every new credit pull will cost you a few points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Make any large cash deposits (unless you have a bill of sale or absolute proof where it came from).&lt;/strong&gt; Cash is a bit of a no-no in the mortgage business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Transfer any funds from one bank account to another.&lt;/strong&gt; This makes our job more complicated. It means we have to get statements proving where that money came from and what it was for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Don’t switch banks.&lt;/strong&gt; Things are much simpler if you just stick with one bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Don’t co-sign for anything.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people think this is okay as long as someone else makes the payments, but it’s not. We still have to count that against you—particularly if you co-signed less than 12 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this or any other mortgage topic, just give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/12-things-to-avoid-doing-during-the-loan-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/12-things-to-avoid-doing-during-the-loan-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Combat Indecision in Today's Fast-Paced Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTJwc_NX4OQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to talk about the effects of a fast-moving market. Recently, I’ve been hearing from a lot of frustrated buyers who are tired of losing out on homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oftentimes the reason they lost out was that they told their Realtor they needed time to think.&lt;/strong&gt; When the client calls their Realtor back with the decision to buy, they do so only to find out the home has already gone under contract with someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is frustrating for the buyer and their agent alike. In this market, you must be prepared to make fast decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I truly think this is a great strategy for undecided buyers to utilize.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-to-combat-indecision-in-todays-fast-paced-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I truly think this is a great strategy for undecided buyers to utilize.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many Realtors tell me that any home under $250,000 in our area is likely to move off the market in just one or two days. This doesn’t leave buyers with time to wait around and think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a great solution here is to take advantage of the 10-day option period our Texas real estate contracts provide. The beauty of this period is that you can go under contract but still think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking advantage of this option period costs just $100, which is well worth it if you’re unsure of whether you want to commit but are afraid of missing out.&lt;/strong&gt; If you decide during that 10-day period that the property isn’t the right home for you, all you’ve lost out on is that option check. You will get your earnest money back. I truly think this is a great strategy for undecided buyers to utilize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-to-combat-indecision-in-todays-fast-paced-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-to-combat-indecision-in-todays-fast-paced-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Future Property Located in a Flood Zone?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SNVXC6dqCuQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it crucial when buying a property that you check if it’s located in a flood zone? Let me tell you a quick story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing a loan for a couple who bought a 12-acre property awhile back but didn’t know that part of the property was in a flood zone. Since they only recently learned about this and we’ve pulled a flood certificate, they now have to pay between $100 and $200 a month extra for the entire life of their loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use a Realtor to buy a property, make sure they work hard to check for this kind of information. &lt;strong&gt;Most of the time, if a property is located within a flood zone, that fact will be listed in the seller’s disclosure.&lt;/strong&gt;Some sellers themselves don’t even know if their property is located in a flood zone, though. This could be because they inherited the property, bought it at an auction, or the land was split off from another parcel. Sometimes, unfortunately, they can also be dishonest and just not tell you about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, again, you should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it. If you’re using a mortgage to finance the purchase, ask your lender to run what’s called a “flood cert” (or flood certificate), where they reach out to FEMA and FEMA reports back to them whether the property is located either partially or wholly within a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have that flood certificate, it will put your home into a certain category. You can then give this information to your insurance agent and they can tell you to what extent your flood insurance will cost you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the property is only located partially within a flood zone, &lt;strong&gt;you can ask a surveyor to provide an elevation certificate,&lt;/strong&gt; which may show that the home site where you plan on building is not in a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about flood insurance or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
