<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guild Mortgage with Patrick Fitzgerald</title>
    <description>Patrick Fitzgerald, the VA Loan Guy, is located in San Antonio, Texas and is a true “One Stop Lender”. We originate, underwrite, and close all types of loans. We offer Texas Vet, Veterans, FHA, Conventional, Jumbo, Adjustable Rate, and Investment products.</description>
    <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.thevaloanguy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 16:45:08 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 16:45:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Home Warranties Are so Important</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_QKJ6tuUkhs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying a home today, receiving a clean report from the home inspector does not mean you are out of the woods. &lt;strong&gt;Systems or appliances in your home could fail a week, a month, or even years down the line.&lt;/strong&gt; And they may no longer be under warranty, meaning that you will be the one to pay if something goes wrong. That is, if you do not have a home warranty policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a home warranty policy can protect you from such expenses. &lt;strong&gt;You will be offered such a policy at closing, but it is still possible to obtain a home warranty even after this point.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense. Systems and appliances like stoves, dishwashers, garage door openers, air conditioning units, water heaters, and more are among the items these policies cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These policies ensure that if, and when, something breaks down or stops working in your home, you will be protected against what could otherwise be a major expense.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, given how catastrophic a cost replacing or repairing these items could be, it is clear why a home warranty is so critical. Think of it this way: Wouldn’t you rather pay a fixed cost for a home warranty policy each year rather than shelling out who knows how much for an unexpected disaster? There are some exceptions, but &lt;strong&gt;for the most part, the only cost you pay when ordering a repair through your home warranty policy is the charge for the service call.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last decade as a homeowner, I have had two air conditioning units, my dishwasher, my garbage disposal, and my garage door spring all fail. You never know when a system or appliance in your home may fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if a standard policy isn’t sufficient for your needs, you may consider signing up for a premium or enhanced policy. These offer even more protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between your real estate agent and title company, you will have access to a wealth of knowledge and resources in the process of selecting which home warranty policy is right for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 14:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-home-warranties-are-so-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Homeowner’s Insurance Policy Should You Choose?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFzjL8xCMoE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of questions about homeowners insurance from clients as well as Realtors. So, today I’d like to discuss a few important points about this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rates are going up sharply due to some pretty massive national losses from a lot of the insurance companies. Hurricane flooding in Houston and other natural disasters in California are creating massive claims for insurance companies, driving up the costs. But, you should know that &lt;strong&gt;if you are going to finance the home, homeowner’s insurance is mandatory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, insurance companies try to get your business by offering you a low rate. However, they increase the deductible over the usual 1% deductible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you have a $250,000 house with a total roof loss due to hail and a new roof costs $10,000. To reach your deductible you will have to pay $2,500, which means you will get a check for $7,500 to pay for your roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you elected to take a 2% or even a 3% deductible, you are going to get next to nothing for that roof. Since the roof still needs to be repaired, this can take a major toll on your checkbook. For this reason, you should &lt;strong&gt;be careful what deductible you select&lt;/strong&gt; when you choose coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should select a policy with a 1% deductible even if it has a higher rate because if something does happen a higher deductible could mean you spend more.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should select a policy with a 1% deductible even if it has a higher rate because if something does happen a higher deductible could mean you spend more.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many coverage options available today. &lt;strong&gt;You should select replacement coverage.&lt;/strong&gt; This type of coverage means that if you have a fire and all of your furniture is destroyed, you will get brand-new furniture even though it may be old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foundation, sometimes called slab, coverage will protect you from cracking due to covered events.&lt;/strong&gt; You also want water coverage for any seepage of water or broken pipes in the slab. Water can cause a tremendous amount of damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What controls the rates you get, though? &lt;strong&gt;Credit scores, the age of the home, the age of the roof, and location all influence your rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people also wonder about bundling their insurance and if they will get a deal. When you combine your auto insurance and homeowners insurance with the same company, you can get discounts on both. Always ask for the bundle deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about insurance, you can go to the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opic.texas.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Office of Public Insurance Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;’s website. Here, they have information about homeowners insurance broken down into coverage, what it means, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions for me, please feel free to contact me by phone or email. I would be happy to assist in any way that I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:33:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/what-homeowners-insurance-policy-should-you-choose.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>12 Things to Avoid Doing During the Loan Process</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HlHj2u-q6nk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick rundown of the top 12 things you should not do during the loan process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Quit your job (or change jobs).&lt;/strong&gt; Why is this important? The day before closing, we have to call your employer to make sure you’re still there. If you quit, retire, or change jobs, that will be known the day before closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Buy a new car.&lt;/strong&gt; All mortgage companies have to do a soft credit pull the day of or the day before closing to make sure you haven’t taken on any new debt. If you purchase a new car, that will be revealed during a soft credit pull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Max out your credit card(s).&lt;/strong&gt; If you max out any credit cards, the minimum payment on your credit report goes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Let any collections show up on your credit report.&lt;/strong&gt; Even something as small as a co-pay at the doctor’s office can upset your approval because that collection can cost you 30 to 40 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Spend the money you set aside for your closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; Believe it or not, this does happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure you avoid doing any of these things during the loan process.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/12-things-to-avoid-doing-during-the-loan-process.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure you avoid doing any of these things during the loan process.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Omit any liabilities (childcare costs, private land payments, etc.).&lt;/strong&gt; Eventually, these will come out, and it’s much better if we know about them up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Buy any major appliances or furniture a day or two before closing.&lt;/strong&gt; I know it’s tempting to do so, but if you take on any debt during the loan process, we’ll have to count that payment. Even if the payment is interest-only, we still have to count it on the credit report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Apply for more credit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every new credit pull will cost you a few points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Make any large cash deposits (unless you have a bill of sale or absolute proof where it came from).&lt;/strong&gt; Cash is a bit of a no-no in the mortgage business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Transfer any funds from one bank account to another.&lt;/strong&gt; This makes our job more complicated. It means we have to get statements proving where that money came from and what it was for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Don’t switch banks.&lt;/strong&gt; Things are much simpler if you just stick with one bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Don’t co-sign for anything.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people think this is okay as long as someone else makes the payments, but it’s not. We still have to count that against you—particularly if you co-signed less than 12 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions about this or any other mortgage topic, just give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:59:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/12-things-to-avoid-doing-during-the-loan-process.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/12-things-to-avoid-doing-during-the-loan-process.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Combat Indecision in Today's Fast-Paced Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTJwc_NX4OQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’d like to talk about the effects of a fast-moving market. Recently, I’ve been hearing from a lot of frustrated buyers who are tired of losing out on homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oftentimes the reason they lost out was that they told their Realtor they needed time to think.&lt;/strong&gt; When the client calls their Realtor back with the decision to buy, they do so only to find out the home has already gone under contract with someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is frustrating for the buyer and their agent alike. In this market, you must be prepared to make fast decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I truly think this is a great strategy for undecided buyers to utilize.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-to-combat-indecision-in-todays-fast-paced-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I truly think this is a great strategy for undecided buyers to utilize.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many Realtors tell me that any home under $250,000 in our area is likely to move off the market in just one or two days. This doesn’t leave buyers with time to wait around and think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a great solution here is to take advantage of the 10-day option period our Texas real estate contracts provide. The beauty of this period is that you can go under contract but still think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking advantage of this option period costs just $100, which is well worth it if you’re unsure of whether you want to commit but are afraid of missing out.&lt;/strong&gt; If you decide during that 10-day period that the property isn’t the right home for you, all you’ve lost out on is that option check. You will get your earnest money back. I truly think this is a great strategy for undecided buyers to utilize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-to-combat-indecision-in-todays-fast-paced-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/how-to-combat-indecision-in-todays-fast-paced-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Future Property Located in a Flood Zone?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SNVXC6dqCuQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it crucial when buying a property that you check if it’s located in a flood zone? Let me tell you a quick story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing a loan for a couple who bought a 12-acre property awhile back but didn’t know that part of the property was in a flood zone. Since they only recently learned about this and we’ve pulled a flood certificate, they now have to pay between $100 and $200 a month extra for the entire life of their loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use a Realtor to buy a property, make sure they work hard to check for this kind of information. &lt;strong&gt;Most of the time, if a property is located within a flood zone, that fact will be listed in the seller’s disclosure.&lt;/strong&gt;Some sellers themselves don’t even know if their property is located in a flood zone, though. This could be because they inherited the property, bought it at an auction, or the land was split off from another parcel. Sometimes, unfortunately, they can also be dishonest and just not tell you about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, again, you should always research if a property is located within a flood zone before you buy it. If you’re using a mortgage to finance the purchase, ask your lender to run what’s called a “flood cert” (or flood certificate), where they reach out to FEMA and FEMA reports back to them whether the property is located either partially or wholly within a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have that flood certificate, it will put your home into a certain category. You can then give this information to your insurance agent and they can tell you to what extent your flood insurance will cost you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the property is only located partially within a flood zone, &lt;strong&gt;you can ask a surveyor to provide an elevation certificate,&lt;/strong&gt; which may show that the home site where you plan on building is not in a flood zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about flood insurance or there’s anything else I can help you with, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/is-your-future-property-located-in-a-flood-zone.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Should You Work With My Own Realtor</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qzofkoWL0hA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to talk about why you need your own Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When driving around looking for a home, you might come across a house you like with a yard sign featuring a phone number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are tempted to pick up the phone and call, but you need to know that the number on the sign is for a Realtor who represents the seller. They have a signed contract with that homeowner, &lt;strong&gt;meaning that they’re not financially obligated to represent your interests, and don’t have to inform you about any known issues in the house.&lt;/strong&gt; They have no fiduciary responsibility to you as a buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s important for you to have your own Realtor. When you have your own representation, &lt;strong&gt;it doesn’t cost you anything because the selling fees are paid for by the seller of the property.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A buyer’s agent will represent you and only you. They’re obligated to protect your interests. Your Realtor will work in conjunction with the seller’s agent to negotiate the best deal for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to me. Remember, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 13:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/why-should-you-work-with-my-own-realtor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Difference Between an Inspection and an Appraisal?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JRhBnrjmW3s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between an inspection and an appraisal? Today, I’d like to clear up some key differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many veterans call me believing that the VA is going to do an inspection on their home, when in fact, that’s not really the case. &lt;strong&gt;The VA will appraise a home, not inspect it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An appraiser is there to view the property, measure it for square footage, take pictures of the home, and study the property as a whole to determine its value.&lt;/strong&gt; This is done by comparing it to other properties with similar square footage and amenities that have sold in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inspector, on the other hand, couldn’t care less about the value of the property. &lt;strong&gt;Inspectors are there to measure the home’s functionality.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, the inspector’s goal is to make sure that the air conditioning and heating system is working, any appliances are fully functional, the electrical framework is up to scratch, and that there are no safety issues in the house. The inspector will generate a 35- to 40-page document with pictures of anything of interest found that needs to be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, the VA does not require a veteran to get an inspection of the home they’re buying. Personally, I would never buy a house without an inspection, but under the terms of the VA loan, they’re not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk to me. Feel free to give me a call and I’d be happy to answer all of your questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 09:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/whats-the-difference-between-an-inspection-and-an-appraisal.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mortgage Loan Rules for Moving a Manufactured Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1LBPTduFqd0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to clarify the rules on moving a manufactured home. A lot of people don’t know this, but there are some very, very specific rules regarding this topic and there’s a lot of confusion about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is this so important?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lender may not be able to do one of the top three loans—FHA, conventional, or VA loan—on a manufactured home if it’s been moved. FHA and conventional loans don’t allow a home to be moved or reinstalled once it has been in installed in its original location. Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the trip from the manufacturer to the location count as a move?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No, it doesn’t count as a move. But here’s what you need to know: If the owner sells the home or has been foreclosed upon, if the home is moved from where it was installed to another location after having been sold, then that is considered a move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Only VA loans, the loan option for veterans, allow the option to move a home once after its initial installation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do we get all this information?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can visit the Texas Department of Housing website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.TDHCA.state.tx.us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.TDHCA.state.tx.us&lt;/a&gt; for records on every installation of manufactured homes. A manufactured home installer is licensed and by law they must log on to that site, enter their license number, then tag numbers of the manufactured home and the serial numbers and declare that they installed a specific home with both the date and location of that installation. This site is how lenders find out if a home has been moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is critical information no matter if you’re on the buyer’s or seller’s side because some lenders don’t even know how to do this. You should want to know in advance if you’re wasting your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this, feel free to give me a call or send an email. I’ll answer all of your questions, and after all, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/mortgage-loan-rules-for-moving-a-manufactured-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Can Veterans Get a Home Improvement Loan?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mwWt0NNZn-4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a veteran looking for a home improvement loan to make some upgrades to your home, I have good news and bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad news is the VA doesn’t offer any loans for this purpose. &lt;strong&gt;The good news is the Texas Veterans Land Board does,&lt;/strong&gt; and they recently doubled the amount they’re willing to loan to a veteran—$50,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple very favorable terms to this loan. Not only will they go up to 20 years on the loan at below market rate, but you don’t have to provide a down payment either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You don’t even need a down payment with this loan.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You don’t even need a down payment with this loan.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply for this loan, just go online at &lt;a href=&quot;www.texasveterans.com&quot;&gt;www.texasveterans.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; From there, they’ll contact you to get the ball rolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the requirements for this loan is you need to gather two bids for the work you want to be done—they won’t allow you to do it yourself. After they underwrite and approve the loan, the work will begin. Typically, they’ll send the money to a local title company in your area. As soon as the work is done, they’ll send an inspector to your home to ensure the work has been done satisfactorily and you’re happy with it. After that, they’ll fund the work and make sure the suppliers get paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are home improvement loans available for non-veterans too. They’re typically done by most banks or federal credit unions, and most of them are underwritten by HUD. If you’d like to know more about these, ask your local bank or credit union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about home improvement loans, don’t hesitate to give me a call. As always, it doesn’t cost a penny to talk, and I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 07:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/where-can-veterans-get-a-home-improvement-loan.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Unique Opportunity for Veteran Homebuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7lioYYtkhK4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can not only use VA financing to buy a home with 0% down, but you can also use VA financing to buy a multi-family property? If you set things up right, the home will essentially pay for itself. Here’s what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are allowed to use a VA loan to purchase a multi-family property, but there are a few caveats.&lt;/strong&gt; First, you must occupy the property as a primary residence within 60 days of closing on the property. That’s a very important rule to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=This is a smart investment strategy.%20http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“This is a smart investment strategy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to multi-family properties, you can actually use the projected rent from the other units in the home to count towards your qualifying number. Because of this, you will be able to qualify for a home with a much higher price. You’ll also have the opportunity to make passive income through rent as you own the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have VA disability, you will also have a reduction in your property taxes. If you are 100% service-connected disabled, there are no property taxes whatsoever on the entire complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a lot of ways we can make this work, even if you don’t have any prior experience as a landlord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this program or about anything else, give me a call or send me an email today. It doesn’t cost a penny to talk. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 07:04:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.thevaloanguy.com/a-unique-opportunity-for-veteran-homebuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
